<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CSE6240</title>
    <link>https://gt-cse6240.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CSE6240</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gt-cse6240.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>https://gt-cse6240.github.io/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gt-cse6240.github.io/faq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Where is the instructor today? A CS administrative issue prevents him from attending today.  Hopefully this will be resolved before the Wed lecture.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this class recorded?
No.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I work on homeworks with others? No.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I audit the course or take it pass/fail?  Probably not because of seat demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I add this course?  You can try.  The enrollment as of Sun is &lt;sup&gt;98&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;98&lt;/sub&gt; seats, with a waiting list at &lt;sup&gt;123&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;150&lt;/sub&gt;.  We will be selective in overloads and there are limited seats available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an undergrad: can I take the course? Yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a CS student: can I take the course? Yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this course require a strong math background?  Not really.  There is a fair amount of linear algebra and probability, but from a programming or user point of view, not a mathermatical point of view.  For example: if you can understand the concept of PCA and the 1-5 lines of python required to perform it, that is sufficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the course require a strong programming background?  You should be familiar with python, and willing to put in the time to complete programming assignments.  We&amp;rsquo;ll start off modestly but quickly progress.  You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be an expert, but you might need to put in some extra time to become fast and fluent with python.  In particular, we will use the Anaconda python distribution, ipython notebooks, sklearn, pandas, gensim and tensorflow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are make-up assignments allowed?  No. See the late policy in the syllabus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is this the same course as Winter 2016?  Yes, but the syllabus has changed about 30%.  Instead of emphasizing ML optimization we are going to add back some more text- and nlp-specific content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is this course about?  In a nutshell: machine learning topics for recommender systems, text mining and nlp and deep learning.  With some extras sprinkled in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the instructor&amp;rsquo;s goal for the students for this course?  To gain a basic understanding of text mining techniques, couched in machine learning; to acquire practical skills for text processing and machine learning in python and tensorflow; to improve scholarship skills by preparing a research paper and participating in the advanced topics lectures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not about &amp;ldquo;web search&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;?  Correct. This course was created over a decade ago.  In the interim, web has become synonymous with &amp;ldquo;scale&amp;rdquo; and text mining has evolved into ML and recommender systems.  As such, we adjusted the syllabus last year to reflect these newer emphases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we cover graphs and social media?  Probably not, because of time, but we may touch on this in homeworks or advanced topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s up with the guest speakers?  Exposure to other points-of-view is great for developing context in learning.  They also help cover my travel time as I&amp;rsquo;m a full-time employee of Symantec. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What about the advanced topics?  Ideally I will assign 2-3 papers each lecture for us to review which will cover advanced topics in machine learning, nlp and deep learning.  I&amp;rsquo;ll put together very light slideware to facilitate discussion, but we will discuss and debate as a class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the syllabus a contract? Absolutely not!  I reserve the right to modify the syllabus schedule at any time to adjust for course dynamics.  I do not anticipate changing any aspect of grading, but again: dates may change!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is attendance required?  I do not enforce this via grading, but it&amp;rsquo;s in your best interest to attend to stay on top of material for homeworks, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why random project teams?  It&amp;rsquo;s better distribution of talent for teams, it&amp;rsquo;s how the real world works (your co-workers are essentially random, and you don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily get to pick your work teams), and it faciliates socialization in the class.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>home</title>
      <link>https://gt-cse6240.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gt-cse6240.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course Description&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course will cover the fundamentals of structured &amp;amp; unstructured data analysis for text and multimedia content exploration, with an emphasis on vector space representations and deep learning models.  It will focus on machine learning and algorithms suitable for these tasks, and cover both applications and scholarship.  Students are expected to have previous exposure to data mining and machine learning, and to be comfortable programming in python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;instructors&#34;&gt;Instructors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Andrew Gardner &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:andywocky@gmail.com&#34;&gt;andywocky@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Course time: MW 4:35pm - 5:55pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office hours: W 3:30pm - 4:30pm (tentative)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Office: TBD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;tas&#34;&gt;TAs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hang Su &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hangsu@gatech.edu&#34;&gt;hangsu@gatech.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yuyu Zhang &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:yuyu@gatech.edu&#34;&gt;yuyu@gatech.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zhaoming Wu &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:zhaoming@gatech.edu&#34;&gt;zhaoming@gatech.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Office Hours:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wed, 11 - 12, Hang Su, CSE common area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wed, 12 - 13, Yuyu Zhang, CSE common area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wed, 15 - 16, Zhaoming Wu, CSE common area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;textbook&#34;&gt;Textbook&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no formal textbook for this class.  We will provide links for materials as part of lectures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;piazza-t-square&#34;&gt;Piazza &amp;amp; T-square&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will use &lt;a href=&#34;http://piazza.com/gatech/spring2017/cse6240&#34;&gt;Piazza&lt;/a&gt; for discussion and all announcements. Post your questions there. Our teaching staff and your fellow classmates will help answer them quickly. You can also use Pizza to find project teammates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;T-square will be used for submission of assignments and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;collaboration&#34;&gt;Collaboration&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome everyone to share their experiences in tackling issues and helping each other out, but please do not post your answers, as that may affect the learning experience of your fellow classmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are allowed to loosely collaborate with fellow students, but your assignments should be worked on  independently.  Do not share answers with others.  All GT students must observe the honor code.  Any suspected plagiarism or academic misconduct will be reported and directly handled by the Office of Student Integrity (OSI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grading&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;homework-50-of-grade&#34;&gt;Homework (50% of Grade)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We plan to have 5 homework assignments in total, HW 1 - 5, which will consist of a mix of exercises, programming and other activities.  Homeworks will be due approximately two weeks after release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;projects-30-of-grade&#34;&gt;Projects (30% of Grade)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will assign one major project for the course, due before Spring Break.  This will be more significant in scope than the homeworks, and will require substantial programming effort.  For example, you may be asked to create a web applications for a recommendations system for movies, or an active learning image annotation tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projects teams of four will be randomly assigned.  More details on project grading will be provided when released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-paper-20-of-grade&#34;&gt;Research Paper (20% of Grade)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key skills a graduate student should master is the ability to conduct scholarly research on a topic.  Each student will be required to prepare a research paper of 10-15 pages length.  Topics and format will be discussed after Spring Break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;late-submission-policy&#34;&gt;Late Submission Policy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homework can be submitted up to 1 week late at a penalty of -10% per 24 hr period overdue.
Projects can be submitted up to 1 week late at a flat penalty of 30%.  After 1 week the project will be scored as 0%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;schedule&#34;&gt;Schedule&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Week&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Topic&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Event&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 09&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Abbreviated course (syllabus out)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Course Overview and Linear Algebra Review&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;MLK Holiday &amp;ndash; No Class&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 18&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Data representations &amp;amp; text encoding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 1 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 23&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Embeddings 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 25&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Embeddings 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Jan 30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Machine Learning Review&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 1 due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Recommender Systems 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 2 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 06&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Recommender Systems 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deep learning concepts &amp;amp; overview&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Guest Lecture 1: TensorFlow 1 &amp;amp; autoencoders&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 2 due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Guest Lecture 2: TensorFlow 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 3 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Training &amp;amp; (hyper) parameter tuning&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Experiment design and performance measurement&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Feb 27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deep learning: CNNs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 3 due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deep learning: LSTMs 1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 4 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 06&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deep Learning: LSTMs 2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 08&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Guest lecture 3: Bayesian techniques&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Topic modeling&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 4 due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Sentiment analysis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Project due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spring Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 22&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 27&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Guest lecture 4: Clustering&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paper out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mar 29&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Text clustering&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 5 out&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 03&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exploration vs. exploitation &amp;amp; bandits&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 05&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Probabilistic data structures&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;14&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Count-min sketch&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;HW 5 due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Advanced Topics TBD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;15&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 17&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Advanced Topics TBD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Paper due&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 19&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Advanced Topics TBD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 24&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Guest lecture 5: TBD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Apr 26&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No class&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced topics lectures will be facilitated, interactive classroom discussions of advanced papers related to text mining and natural language processing, deep learning and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>